A Guide to the Hench-Albemarle County Historical Society Papers, 1837-1974
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Hench-Albemarle County Historical Society Papers 1837-1974
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
8159-b
This collection consists of 159 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These papers were given to the Manuscripts Department by Mr. Hench's daughter, Mrs. Oscar W. Underwood, III on January 1, 1975.
Scope and Content Information
This addition to Atcheson L. Hench's-Albemarle County Historical Society collection, 1837-1974, consists of 159 items including his notes on the Society, his collection of 19th Century letters (6), pamphlets, and newspaper clippings regarding the history of the county. Also in these papers are his notes for a talk and an article he prepared for the Society, "The First Ten Years of the Albemarle County Historical Society" and "The Name Albemarle Pippin." There are two papers written by his mother-in-law, Mrs. George R. B. (Haidee) Michie on the Piedmont Hospital, 1866-1902, and on the Park Street School in 1882.
Arrangement
There are 11 folders arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Albemarle County Historical Society: Items collected by A. L. Hench 1837-1903, 6 items. including 4 ALS
- Albemarle County Historical Society: Newspaper Clippings re County History 1918-1950, ca. 41 items
- Two copies of the "History of Piedmont Hospital, 1886-1902," by Mrs. George R. B. (Haidee) Michie 1937, 2 AMssS
- Albemarle County Historical Society: Pamphlets collected by A. L. Hench 1940-1968, 4 items
- Albemarle County Historical Society: Miscellaneous Papers 1940-1973, 6 items
- Albemarle County Historical Society: Speech by Mrs. George R. B. Michie (A. L. Hench's mother-in-law) on the Park Street School 1943 July 27, 1 AMs
- Albemarle County Historical Society: Correspondence and Papers 1945-1971, 11 items
- A. L. Hench's notes and talk: "The First Ten Years of the Albemarle County Historical Society" given at "Cloverfields" 1950 July 14, 3 items
- Albemarle County Historical Society: A. L. Hench's correspondence, notes, and article on the Albemarle Pippin 1955 April 13, ca. 15 items
- Albemarle County Historical Society: Newspaper Clippings re the County 1958-1974, ca. 35 items
- Albemarle County Historical Society: A. L. Hench's notes 1962-1965, ca. 25 items